Guide to the Cross Country and Track and Field records, 1932-ongoing
University Archives Duke University Durham, N.C., USA
Cross Country and Track and Field records 1932-ongoing
University Archives, Duke University
Duke University. Sports Information Office.
11.9 Linear Feet 12,700 Items
The Sports Information Office provides information about Duke athletics to the media. They also facilitate press interviews with Duke athletes and coaches.
The collection includes clippings, press releases, statistics, rosters, programs and press brochures/media guides about the cross country/track and field teams at Duke University. The material ranges in date from 1932-ongoing.
Administrative Information
Access Restrictions
Researchers must register and agree to copyright and privacy laws before using this collection.
Collection is open for research.
Provenance
The Cross Country and Track and Field records were received by the University Archives as a transfer over a period of time.
Historical Note
The Sports Information Office provides information about Duke athletics to the media. They also facilitate press interviews with Duke athletes and coaches. For many years, the SI Office has maintained records, photographs and other material about Duke athletic teams.
Collection Overview
The collection includes clippings, press releases, statistics, rosters, programs and press brochures/media guides about the cross country/track and field teams at Duke University. There are files regarding the freshman varsity track and field team, the Southern Conference teams, the Interscholastic meets, and one folder concerning the 1956 Olympics featuring (Joel Shankle and Dave Sime). The material ranges in date from 1932-ongoing.
Collection Arrangement
The collection is divided into three main series, Cross-Country, Track and Field, and Media Guides.
Subject Headings
These are searchable subject entries for this collection. Performing a search on these subjects in the Duke University Libraries online catalog will bring up other related research materials.
Duke University. Sports Information Office
Duke University -- Cross-country running -- History -- 20th century
Duke University -- Track and field athletes -- History -- 20th century.
Duke University -- Sports
Related Material
Athletic Dept. Records.
University Archives, Duke University.
Scrapbooks.
University Archives, Duke University.
Photograph Collection.
University Archives, Duke University.
Photographic Negative Collection.
University Archives, Duke University.
Chanticleer Photograph Collection.
University Archives, Duke University.
Athletic Council Records.
University Archives, Duke University.
Athletics Reference Collection.
University Archives, Duke University.
Contents of Collection
- Cross-Country, 1932-ongoing, 3 Boxes
  - General Yearly Files, 1932-1999
    The general yearly files contain clippings, press releases, statistics, rosters, and programs about the cross-country team at Duke University. The files may include information about both the men and women's teams.
    - 1932-1974; 1979-1982 (Box 1)
    - 1983-1990; 1998-1999 (Box 2)
  - Men's Cross-County, 1987-1999
    - 1987; 1990-1999 (Box 2)
  - Women's Cross-Country, 1984-2000
    - 1984-1991; 1993-2000 (Box 3)
- Track and Field, 1933-ongoing, 13 Boxes
  - General Yearly Files, 1933-1990; 1999-2000
    The general yearly files contain clippings, press releases, statistics, rosters, and programs about the track and field team at Duke University. The files may include information about both the men and women's teams. Also includes Indoor track.
    - 1933-1936 (Box 4)
    - Includes Southern Conference track, varsity track, and Interscholastic track and field meets
    - 1937-1952 (Box 5)
    - Includes Southern Conference track, varsity and freshmen track
    - 1953-1964 (Box 6)
    - Includes 1956 Olympics (Joel S and Dave Sime), and ACC Track meet held in Durham, 1958
    - 1964-1970 (Box 7)
    - 1970-1974; 1979-1981 (Box 8)
    - 1982-1987 (Box 9)
    - 1988; 1990 (Box 10)
    - 1999 GM-Duke Invite Results
    - 2000 Duke Invitational
    - 1999-2000 Track and Field (7 folders)
    - 1999-2000 Track and Field, continued (6 folders) (Box 11)
    - 1999-2000 Track and Field Division One NCAA meet held at Duke, May 31-June 3, 2000 (6 folders)
  - Men's Track and Field, 1988-1999
    Includes Indoor and Outdoor track
    - 1988-1993 (Box 12)
    - 1993-1999 (Box 13)
  - Women's Track and Field, 1984-1992
    - 1984-1992 (Box 14)
    - 1992-1996 (Box 15)
    - 1996-1999 (Box 16)
- Press Brochures/Media Guides, 1970-ongoing, 1 Box
  - Men, 1970-1998; 2000 (Box 17)
  - Women, 1988-1999; 2002
  - Cross-Country/Track and Field (includes men and women)
    - 2003-2004
    - 2004-2005
    - 2007-2008
    - 2008-2009
  - Men c.2
  - Women c.2